[Episode 3]
What a lovely young lady.
Fine jade suits you.
Why not try this one?
You don't look like you're from Shazhou.
May I have your name?
I'm Shen Zhi Shu, here looking for a friend.
What does your friend look like?
Let me help you.
He's a young man
with a capital accent.
He's slightly less handsome than me,
a notch below me in grace,
and a tiny bit shorter than me.
Mr. Shen.
Huang, I've finally found you.
From the capital to Shazhou,
you've been keeping busy.
Huang, they're driving me crazy.
I've braved the elements,
crossing mountains and rivers.
Finally...
You found a beauty here.
Why are you here?
Young Master knew you'd arrive now
and sent me over.
Wait.
Where is that beauty?
You didn't escape from the dungeon, did you?
An ordinary dungeon can't hold me.
The Ding family
is searching the whole city for you.
Yet look how bold you are. Why are you here?
To solve your urgent problem.
You? How?
The Heihu Crew owns Jiuyou City.
I know you're investigating the arms
and posing as a wealthy Beijian merchant
to approach Ding Chong.
You're here to obtain evidence
of their collusion with officials
in arms trafficking.
And I know this place inside out
because I grew up here.
I've already uncovered all that.
You're of no use to me now.
On the contrary,
you can't take the Imperial Exam
as a fugitive.
It should be you who needs my help.
Please forgive my ignorance.
I should have known better.
Now I've become a fugitive,
banned from the Imperial Exam.
The official rank matters little.
But I can't lose my right to take the exam.
I believe you are a good official
since you're investigating it.
You need a guide,
and I need a way out.
We each take what we need.
You will put an end
to the corruption in Shazhou
as well as clear my name.
You make a valid point.
But I can't get you into the city.
I only have one travel permit,
which I bought at a high price
from Ding Chong.
What a coincidence.
I also have one.
You're so good at picking pockets.
Have you honed such a skill since childhood?
It's for survival.
Since you can forge it, why steal mine?
Jiuyou City opens up every seven days.
To prevent counterfeiting,
they draw a different pattern on the permit
every seven days.
You are so multi-talented.
You are a skilled martial artist.
I will keep the genuine travel permit.
Giving me the fake one?
You always keep a way out for yourself.
It's time. Let's go.
Everyone in Shazhou
complies with the Heihu Crew.
This place is devoid of justice.
Murder and arson happen all the time.
Those are merchants
who couldn't pay protection fees.
See the green light in the skeleton?
The Heihu Crew makes those people's skulls
into everlasting lamps.
The deeper the resentment...
Keep up.
The brighter the glow.
Sneaking in
with a travel permit from seven days ago?
Get in.
Go on.
Come on, guys.
Someone is selling trade permits.
Don't miss out on it.
Let's go. Hurry.
Trade permits
are issued by the imperial court
and verified and filed by the prefects.
They are only for veteran merchants
with outstanding reputations.
How do they have them?
Even strictly controlled items
like salt and iron are openly sold here.
Let alone a piece of paper.
Ding Chong is insatiable,
auctioning the trade permits
to extremely high prices.
The Yan family offended him
and had their papers withheld for six months.
It took them two chests of gold
to redeem those trade permits.
The court opened border trade
to benefit the border people,
but the parasites
are amassing wealth through it.
You won't find such quality elsewhere.
All good stuff.
Take a look. All good stuff.
Why isn't anyone dealing arms?
It's a serious matter,
involving the military.
Even Ding Chong wouldn't dare do it openly.
His backer in the military
is probably even more cautious.
Mr. He.
What would you do without me as your guide?
I have my own ways.
But seeing you so confident,
I'd like to know your plan.
Follow me.
Walking the path with a lamp,
is it light or dark?
With mist obscuring the way,
I follow the crowd,
not speaking of light or dark.
Miss Meng.
The young man you brought this time
is far better than those previous ones.
But he looks so grumpy.
Anyone would think he's a debt collector.
He doesn't just look grumpy.
He has a bad temper.
Arrogant and conceited,
looking down on everyone,
and self-important.
My distinguished guest,
what would you like to inquire about?
There is nothing
I don't know about Shazhou.
I want to buy arms from the Heihu Crew.
Can you show us the way?
He even found out
the arms are with the Heihu Crew.
Arms trade
is a dangerous line of work.
Forget it. I'll look elsewhere.
You do have a bad temper.
I'll show you the way right now.
As they say, money makes the world go around.
It's more like,
"The native always has the edge."
Without me, we don't know what you would...
We're here.
Mr. Feng gave instructions long ago.
If you mind your own business in Jiuyou City,
you're an honored guest.
But if you act suspiciously
and plot anything,
we'll send you on your way.
Are you fine, Miss Meng?
Are you fine, Mr. He?
What a fine guide you found, Miss Meng.
He certainly pointed us to a unique path.
Stop being sarcastic.
You had to mention the arms trade
and gave us away.
This cave is sealed shut.
We're not going to die here, right?
Since I brought you here,
I won't let anything happen to you.
What's that sound?
Be careful.
The banded krait is deadly.
A master like you
is afraid of a little snake?
Of course not.
I'm afraid of its venom.
Well, I'm not.
You have so many tricks up your sleeve.
You promised to keep me safe.
I'm counting on you.
Low on phosphorus powder.
Talisman paper.
Let's go.
There's a draft.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
Luckily, my buddy Ding Chong
is one step ahead.
That He fellow
posed as a rich merchant to spy on us.
I bet he has a death wish.
Exactly. He thinks he's so capable.
He didn't know
Governor Ding had already looked into them.
Those two should be dead
in the snake pit by now.
Of course.
No one has ever come out of there alive.
They want to infiltrate us?
Let them come. We'll bury them here.
Buddies.
The snake pit connects underground
to the Heihu Crew.
It saved us quite a bit of effort.
That scar-face is Feng Lu,
the leader of the Heihu Crew.
They have numbers. We can only outwit them.
Capture the leader first.
Guys, keep drinking.
- Yeah!
Is there a fire?
Master, I think I saw him.
Who?
Who is it?
Don't move.
Master.
Come closer if you want your master dead.
Young man,
I know you're investigating the arms.
But going against the Heihu Crew
is going against Governor Ding.
The consequences are more than you can bear.
Mr. Feng.
Be it the Heihu Crew or Ding Chong,
do you really think I care?
Salt, medicinal herbs,
tea, porcelain...
Here are the transaction details
of Jiuyou City.
The profit from porcelain alone
accounts for a year's tax revenue of Shazhou.
[Distribution of spoils]
The division of the spoils is quite clear.
One share each
for the Heihu Crew and Ding Chong,
and the last one just says
"for military".
Too afraid to write down that person's name?
You're so rampant in arms trading.
I imagine the person colluding with you
has a high rank in the army.
Just the two of you want to interrogate me?
Confess now.
Why don't you figure it out yourself?
Since we've found the ledger,
naturally it's all your doing.
Feng Lu set up registration fees
for the women's exam without permission,
manipulated the Jiuyou City market,
selling trade permits,
extorting the merchants...
Stop talking nonsense!
I didn't do any of that.
I only kill people.
Feng Lu alone trafficked arms
with military personnel.
I don't even know where the military camp is.
It was Wang...
Wang Qi.
The military governor of Shazhou.
He's been here for years
and has some prestige.
He's been stationed here
since the previous reign
and has made great achievements
with General Gao Meng.
Throughout those years of duty
with so many subordinates to support,
he's probably just a businessman now,
rather than a general.
It seems you have a deep understanding
of humans' greedy nature.
So Mr. Feng bribed Wang Qi.
I said I didn't do anything.
Who doesn't want money these days?
Who'd turn down a profitable business
like arms trading?
Wang Qi and Ding Chong go way back.
Ding Chong told Wang Qi,
"Even the sturdiest armor
can't withstand the arrow of gold."
[Testimony]
Here is the testimony you just gave.
Sign and put your handprint
if there's no problem.
I can't read.
[Feng Lu]
I just signed it for you. Take it.
Come on, put your handprint.
You act with such decisiveness,
rivaling even the Ministry of Justice.
Mr. He.
We have the testimony.
All we need is the arms ledger.
Who bought the arms from you?
Where is the real arms ledger?
I don't know the buyers.
I've never seen the arms ledger.
Our Heihu Crew is just a courier.
We deliver goods for money, hand to hand.
Still trying to protect Ding Chong
at this point?
If you're in trouble,
the first thing he'll do is kill you.
Once you're dead,
he will slaughter all your buddies.
He can easily
find ten other helpers like you.
Greetings, Governor Ding.
Governor Ding, someone caught our master.
Please save him.
- Is everyone here?
- Yes.
Good. Charge with me.
Alright, guys. Charge in to save our master!
- Charge in!
- Let's go!
Sixth Master!
The Heihu Crew trafficked arms
and committed heinous crimes.
Today, I'm here to annihilate them,
carrying out heaven's justice.
Spare no one.
Master.
That traitor Ding Chong
brought troops to encircle us.
Our guys are either dead or injured.
Ding Chong came even faster than I thought.
My buddies.
Ding Chong, you filthy traitor!
I'm going to kill him!
Hand over the real ledger,
and I'll spare your life.
It's under my bed.
Let me go.
He has some backbone.
Why did Ding Chong come?
You personally
delivered the order for Lord Xu.
I am truly flattered.
Lord Xu sent me here
to save your life for old time's sake.
I am dull-witted. Please enlighten me.
The court has sent secret envoys to Shazhou
to investigate the arms trafficking.
Could it be that He fellow?
Lord Xu said
that if you want to come out unscathed,
you'd better get rid of the Heihu Crew soon.
Then you can pin everything on them.
After all, dead men
can't cry out their grievances.
Lord Xu is far-sighted.
I share the very same view as him.
I'll handle it immediately.
Ding Chong!
Three years ago, you injured your leg.
If I hadn't carried you
from Qingzhou to Shazhou,
the wolves would have eaten you up.
All these years,
I've treated you like a brother.
But you killed all of my buddies.
Feng, if you're my brother,
just do me this favor.
You have to die for me to live.
Ding Chong!
- Surround this place. Leave no one alive.
- Understood.
Stop, all of you.
Mr. Shen.
The Heihu Crew is steeped in evil.
I've executed their leader Feng Lu.
Cousin.
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
How dare you, Ding Chong!
Your crimes are monstrous. Surrender now!
Seize him.
Mr. Shen.
Is there some misunderstanding?
Huang Bo.
Ding Chong,
as a court official,
you colluded with the Heihu Crew
to traffic arms for personal gain
and killed witnesses.
Killing you ten times
still wouldn't quell the people's hatred.
Who are you?
I can see you hold a high position.
All crows are equally black.
Why must we give each other a hard time?
Tell me what you want.
Let me go,
and I'll give you 10,000 taels of gold.
No amount of gold can redeem your sin.
Ding Chong has been arrested.
Before it gets out of control,
lay down your weapons,
and you still get to atone for your crimes.
But if you continue to resist,
you'll be considered his accomplice.
Hurry up.
Take Ding Chong and the others back
for interrogation.
Locate the arms.
Mr. Shen.
Protect the young master.
Huang Bo, get that person.
Understood.
Such penetration.
It must be forged from refined iron.
The same material
as the army's smuggled arrows.
Are they melting down the arms
to reforge weaponry?
Only an insider could kill Ding Chong
at the perfect time.
In that real arms ledger,
a huge quantity of arms is unaccounted for.
That person in black
is probably connected to the arms buyer.
The pattern is quite distinctive.
We must look into
this person and the crossbow bolt.
Governor.
Take him away.
Take everyone back.
- Let me go!
- Leave no one behind.
- Move.
- Governor.
Ding Chong is dead.
You are no longer a fugitive.
I'll have Mr. Shen redocument your dossier
for the Imperial Exam.
Now, we're finally even.
Run. They're here to confiscate everything.
Put it here.
Hurry up.
Mother, what's going on?
Keep it down.
Your uncle is dead.
People are getting arrested everywhere.
Change into these and come with me.
This is hideous. I won't wear it.
I'd rather die.
Do as I say or you'll die.
Put it on.
Hurry.
It stinks.
We're running out of time! Hurry!
Hurry.
Alright.
Your Majesty.
Wang Qi and the generals in Shazhou
have been arrested.
Evidence and testimonies have been stored.
Seal the news
and escort them secretly back to the capital.
- Must keep this from the Left Chancellor.
- Understood.
Your Majesty.
Ding Chong's gang has been wiped out.
His properties in Jiuyou City
have all been sealed.
All involved merchants have been punished
according to the law.
It was a huge success.
Your Majesty,
we should head back to the capital.
Lord Xu's deadline is only three days away.
Are you telling me to obey him?
I wouldn't dare.
We follow Your Majesty's orders.
Your father, Grand Tutor Shen,
is going to supervise the Provincial Exam.
He should be here soon.
I need to discuss the matters
with him in detail.
After that, we'll depart overnight.
Then we'll surely arrive in time.
And keep a close eye
on Meng Ting Hui's grade
in the Imperial Exam.
Your Majesty, have you taken a fancy to her?
Taken a fancy?
She swindles, cheats,
plays tricks, and acts like a rogue.
It's hard not to be impressed.
Your Majesty's intention is fully understood.
I will certainly
prevent such a hooligan
from entering the court.
Huang, you're really getting better
at guessing His Majesty's intentions.
I've been serving His Majesty for years.
I mean to say that her street wisdom
sometimes works better
than high principles in court.
His Majesty fancies her.
Don't you understand?
Huang Bo, do you remember this place?
Ten years ago, there was a great drought
where sandstorms raged.
To fix the sand,
Your Majesty brought people to plant poplars.
Now, the desert has given way to greenery.
Every time I come to Shazhou,
the things I experience get more thrilling.
Do you remember the girl
who stole my jade pendant?
Yes, I remember her. She was coerced.
Because of her,
Your Majesty
took down the child trafficking gang.
Xiang, have this.
Let's go.
Where to?
Bofeng.
I heard Bofeng
is a new restaurant in Shazhou.
The lamb noodles are a local specialty.
I'd been observing a vegetarian diet
on your behalf
before I traveled all the way here.
I have starved so much that I've lost weight.
How come I don't see it?
Master, Ding Chong and Feng Lu are dead.
Those greedy Ning Empire lackeys
have become useless.
I don't care if they died.
Master, we may have
acquired some weapons over the years,
but it's far from enough.
Now that we've lost this channel,
we may have to find another way.
Our top priority is to hide our tracks.
No one shall discover who we are.
Understood.
I think the days of the Ning Empire
are numbered.
Fire!
Guards. Put out the fire!
Meng, it's me.
Fu Zhi, what are you doing?
Luck hasn't been on our side.
I'm repelling your bad luck.
Repelling my bad luck?
Meng, you're amazing.
Shazhou is finally going to see justice done.
It's just that Jiang Mei Er disappeared.
She got off easy.
Heaven will deal with the wicked.
Fu Zhi, can you take this away first?
I have good news for you.
Bofeng is finally mine.
Business is booming.
Xi Er and Hai Tang are overwhelmed.
My father canceled that awful engagement.
You should see my stepmother's face.
She looked like
she had swallowed a hundred flies.
I'll go to Bofeng with you
and wait for Mr. He.
He's holding my dossier.
I can't be at ease until I get it back.
- Right.
- Take it away.
No way. We're removing bad luck.
Come on, left hand.
Right hand.
Left foot.
Turn around.
Fu Zhi.
My dossier.
Shouldn't you buy me a meal?
To enjoy lamb noodles, drink the soup first.
Warm soup really whets the appetite.
Okay, I'll try.
I've come to Shazhou before,
but I never knew this delicacy.
Try this, a Shazhou specialty.
You've been here before?
I came in a hurry
and didn't have time for sightseeing.
We had a rough start,
but now we know each other.
I brought your dossier.
One bowl of noodles is not enough.
I'm returning to the capital soon.
I wonder if you'd be willing
to show me around.
The Provincial Exam is imminent.
Every second counts.
I need to study.
Without the dossier, how are you...
You're quite something.
Where should we go?
Can you ride a horse?
Miss Meng, your riding is truly impressive.
Galloping across the vast desert
feels so free.
You're brave, resourceful,
and full of life wisdom.
I'm curious about your upbringing.
I had no parents
and was abducted by traffickers.
They taught me to steal and cheat
to make money for them.
My "bravery and resourcefulness"
are only necessities for survival.
A beating would be getting off easy.
I could have died.
You little brat, you want to kill me?
Xiang, run!
Miss Meng, what's on your mind?
Just the past.
Shazhou is a place of bright sunshine,
yet lacks justice.
Officials do nothing.
I'm taking the Imperial Exam
not only to protect myself,
but also to hold power,
so that the wicked
can't oppress the common people.
You have a great ambition.
I can offer you a shortcut.
My uncle, Grand Tutor Shen,
is coming to preside over the exam.
Why don't we ask Mr. Shen to introduce you?
Everyone knows Grand Tutor Shen
is a man of integrity.
But you offered to introduce me to him.
Why does it sound like you're setting me up?
When it comes to setting people up,
you're the expert.
It's just that you helped me
take down the corrupt officials and the gang.
I have no way to repay you,
so I'll lend you a hand.
Look at that tree.
It knows how to grow by leaning on the dune.
That's why they grow
much taller than the poplars.
Sometimes going with the flow
is the way to break the deadlock.
The way of survival in the desert
isn't about who's taller,
but whose roots are deeper.
I know my place.
Having a friend like you in the capital
would be adding wings to a tiger.
But I prefer to make it all by myself.
May everything go
as you wish, then.
To the rightful owner.
Consider this a thank-you gift
for helping me solve the case.
We've finally settled our accounts.
Don't put me in debt again.
Miss Meng.
Until we meet again.
If we're meant to meet again, we will.